Guide to the Records of the Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture RG.37.13
New York University Archives
Records of the Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture
1966-2000
New York University Archives
New York University. Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture
RG.37.13
7 linear feet in 5 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 3 flat boxes, and 1 small media box
177 audiocassettes
69 videocassettes (u-matic)
5 videocassettes (vhs)
The Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture at New York University is part of a network grouped within the Center for French Civilization and Culture. The Center exists to promote academic and cultural activity of the University's four significant spheres of French Studies: the Department, the Institute of French Studies, NYU-Paris, and La Maison Française. The extensive range of courses in language, visual arts, history, literature, and French politics permit students to immerse themselves in French intellectual and cultural life. This collection consists of audiovisual recordings created and collected by the department from the 1960s through the early 2000s. Materials include the department's collection of audiovisual recordings of theatre screenings, television segments, interviews, and lectures revolving around French creative arts, politics, literature, and film theory. The collection also includes sound recordings of lectures, readings, symposia, roundtable discussions, and gallery talks on contemporary perspectives of the French and Francophone language, literature, and civilization held at New York University's La Maison Française.
Arrangement
Organized into two series:
Series I. Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture Audiovisual Recordings
Series II. La Maison Française Sound Recordings
Within each series the recordings are arranged chronologically.
Historical Note
The Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture at New York University is part of a network grouped within the Center for French Civilization and Culture. Professor Tom Bishop founded the Center in 1978 and was its director until 2016. The Center exists to promote academic and cultural activity of the University's four significant spheres of French Studies: the Department, the Institute of French Studies, NYU-Paris, and La Maison Française.
The Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture offers a comprehensive range of courses in French and Francophone language, literature, film, culture, and civilization for undergraduate students of the College of Arts and Science (CAS) and graduate students of the Graduate School of Arts and Science (GSAS). The extensive range of courses in language, visual arts, history, literature, and French politics permit students to immerse themselves in French intellectual and cultural life. Select courses are taught by prominent visiting professors, which have included Jacques Derrida, Gérard Genette, Alain Robbe-Grillet, Philippe Roger, Françoise Gaillard, Lucette Finas, Tahar Ben Jelloun, and Yves Hersant. Undergraduate and graduate students of the department are also encouraged to pursue studies abroad at NYU Paris.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to the University Archives by the Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture in 2017; the accession number associated with this gift is 2017.040.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of audiovisual recordings created and collected by the Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture from the 1960s through the early 2000s. Materials include the department's collection of audiovisual recordings of theatre screenings, television segments, interviews, and lectures revolving around French creative arts, politics, literature, and film theory. These visual and sound recordings display the literary and artistic thought of leading French writers, including Jacques Derrida, Roland Barthes, Jean Cocteau, and Pierre Assouline. Particular emphasis is placed on the theoretical concepts of theatre, visual art, and film, with discussions evaluating the works of playwrights Samuel Beckett and Eugène Ionesco as well as the performance of stage actor Jean-Louis Barrault. The collection also includes sound recordings of lectures, readings, symposia, roundtable discussions, and gallery talks on contemporary perspectives of the French and Francophone language, literature, and civilization held at New York University's La Maison Française. These audio recordings document events featuring literary, artistic, and political figures, including Robert Badinter, Roland Barthes, and Nathalie Sarraute, in addition to other distinguished guests such as, Michel Butor, Hélène Cixous, Maryse Condé, and Amélie Nothomb.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact university-archives@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
- Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture Audiovisual Recordings, 1969-2000
  Scope and Contents
  The Department of French Audiovisual Recordings consists of video and audio cassette recordings of theatre screenings, television segments, interviews, and lectures revolving around French creative arts, politics, literature, and film theory. These visual and sound recordings display the literary and artistic thought of leading French writers, including Jacques Derrida, Roland Barthes, Jean Cocteau, and Pierre Assouline. Particular emphasis is placed on the theoretical concepts of theatre, visual art, and film, with discussions evaluating the works of playwrights Samuel Beckett and Eugène Ionesco as well as the performance of stage actor Jean-Louis Barrault. Through a selection of seminars, video screenings, and conferences, the Department of French Audiovisual Recordings provides a platform for stimulating discourse for those interested in French intellectual and cultural life.
  - Conversations about Theatre, 1973 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0001)
  - Vanderbilt Television News Archive Segments, 1974-1977 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0002, 37-13.0003)
    According to the labels on the tapes: "Segment 1: CBS 7/14/1969 through CBS 1/6/1976; Segment 2: CBS 2/28/1969 through ABC 1/4/1978; Segment 3: NBC 10/24/1969 through NBC 5/24/1977; Segment 4: NBC 6/16/1969 through NBC 12/18/1974; Segment 5: CBS 11/13/1975 through NBC 11/22/1977"
  - L'Aigle a Deux Tetes, July 24, 1975 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0004, 37-13.0005)
  - Sunrise Semester #13: Cocteau Thomson Interview, October 19, 1976 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0006)
  - Sunrise Semester #12: Theatre, Anouilh, Brecht, October 16, 1976 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0007)
  - Sunrise Semester #17: Giraudoux; Harold Clurman Interview, October 28, 1976 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0008)
  - Sunrise Semester #19: Anouilh (1), John Simon Interview, November 2, 1976 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0009)
  - Sunrise Semester: Genet's The Maids, November 11, 1976 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0010)
  - Sunrise Semester #26 and #27: Sartre No Exit, November 18-20, 1976 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0006, 37-13.0011)
  - Sunrise Semester #32: Genet's The Maids Ritual Scene, December 4, 1976 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0012)
  - Sunrise Semester #33: Genet's The Maids Concluded, December 7, 1976 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0013)
  - Sunrise Semester #34: Ionesco Interview, December 9, 1976 (Box 1, U-matic 37-13.0014)
  - Sunrise Semester #35: Ionesco, Bald Soprano, December 11, 1976 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0015)
  - Sunrise Semester #37: Ionesco - The Lesson Film, December 16, 1976 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0016)
  - Sunrise Semester #39 and #41: Beckett's Waiting for Godot, December 21-28, 1976 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0017, 37-13.0018)
  - Sunrise Semester #45: Alain Robbe-Grillet Interview, January 8, 1976 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0019)
  - Sollers: L'Homme en Question, September 22, 1978 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0020)
  - Blonsky, Barthes Seminar, November 7, 1978 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0021, 37-13.0022)
  - La Part de Verite (G. Suffert), January 31, 1979 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0023)
  - Jean Cocteau Ou La Traversee du Miroir (Encyclopedie Audiovisuelle du Cinema), April 22, 1979 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0024)
  - Theater: Emerging Playwrights Parts V and VIII, June 1, 1979 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0025)
  - Aujour D'hui Madame - Des Auteurs Face a Leurs Lectrices, October 8, 1979 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0026)
  - Une Minute Pour Les Femmes, October 8, 1979 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0027)
  - Les Mercredos d'Aujourd'hui Madame, October 10, 1979 (Box 2, U-matic 37-13.0028)
  - Mi-Fugue Mi-Raison, November 7, 1979 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0029, 37-13.0030)
  - Jean Cocteau, De L'ecriture au Cinematographe (Encyclopedie Audiovisuelle du Cinema), November 4, 1979 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0031)
  - Marianne Sergent (TF1), November 19, 1979 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0032)
  - Si Pres Si, Loin, Montbrison ou L'enfance Retrouvee, December 19, 1979 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0033)
  - Nouveau Vendredi: La Fievre Colombienne, February 2, 1980 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0034)
  - C'est la Vie - L'environment, February 4, 1980 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0035)
  - L'Invite du Jeudi: M. Apfelbaum, May 22, 1980 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0036, 37-13.0037)
  - Grands-Meres: Odette Robert (TF1), July 21, 1980 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0038)
  - A La Recherche de L'Oncle SAM, August 10, 1980 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0039, 37-13.0040)
  - Des Auteurs Face a Leurs Lectrices, September 22, 1980 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0041)
  - La Comedie Francaise, September 30, 1980 (Box 3, U-matic 37-13.0042)
  - Aujourd'hui Madame: La Vie Associative, October 21, 1980 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0043)
  - L'Evenement: Interview de la Shabanou; Les Services Secrets Americains, October 30, 1980 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0044)
  - Fragment de Theatre II: Samuel Beckett, 1981 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0045)
  - Les Gens d'Ici, October 14, 1981 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0046)
  - L'Eloquence Politique, November 6, 1981 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0047)
  - L'Evenement: Le Racisme: Affaire de La Mosquee de Rennes; Le Tremblement de Terre en Algerie; La Greve des Lads, February 12, 1982 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0053)
  - Enigme a Pontaumur, April 19, 1982 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0048)
  - Jean Villar: Debut a 27, May 5, 1982 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0049)
  - Louis Seigner, May 24, 1982 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0050)
  - Apostrophes: La Qualite Francaise, November 26, 1982 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0051, 37-13.0052)
  - Marguerite Duras Rehearsal: Savanah, 1983 (Box 4, Vhs 37-13.0054)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Note on tape says "bad quality"
  - Malraux, July 4, 1983 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0055)
  - The French Deterrence: An Assessment (French Embassy), October 20, 1983 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0056)
  - Domicile Conjugal, December 10, 1984 (Box 4, U-matic 37-13.0057)
  - Parlons Francais, February 5, 1985 (Box 5, U-matic 37-13.0058)
  - Parlons Francais II (Judi Hodnett), June, 1985 (Box 5, U-matic 37-13.0059, 37-13.0060)
  - Jean-Louis Barrault: A Man of the Theater (Un Homme de Theatre), January 24, 1989 (Box 5, U-matic 37-13.0061, 37-13.0062)
  - Deconstruction Roundtable, October 8, 1993 (Box 5, Vhs 37-13.0063)
  - TB Ockrent: Pierre Lescure, June 6, 1994 (Box 5, Vhs 37-13.0064)
  - Pavel: "Creativity + The Arts in France", 1996-03-07 (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0075)
  - Beckett Conference Tape I, August 8, 1996 (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0076)
  - Helene Cixous, October 3, 1996 (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0077)
  - Jacques Derrida: French Theory in America Event: "Deconstructions: I'm Impossible", October 7, 1997 (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0078, 37-13.0079)
  - Richard Sennett: Ethical Legacy of Michel Foucault, November 13, 1997 (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0080, 37-13.0081)
  - Grand Salon, 1999 (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0082, 37-13.0083, 37-13.0084)
  - Beckett at Lincoln Center, undated (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0085)
  - Bouillon de Culture: Edith Piaf, undated (Box 6, Vhs 37-13.0065)
  - Florence Gould Lecture: Criticism of French Intellectual and Artistic Life, undated (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0086)
  - Gaye Sirow (Copy) [illegible], undated (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0087)
  - Jean-Louis Barrault: The Body Speaks (One Man Show in Words and Mime Poems), undated (Box 6, U-matic 37-13.0066)
  - Lecon de Musique (Pierre Schefer), undated (Box 6, U-matic 37-13.0067)
  - Lulu, undated (Box 6, U-matic 37-13.0068, 37-13.0069, 37-13.0070, Box 5)
  - The Maids, undated (Box 6, Vhs 37-13.0071)
  - Pierre Assouline, undated (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0088)
  - Prof. Regalado Baudelaire: Les Fleurs du mal, undated (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0089)
  - Sunrise Semester Dramatic Scenes: Three Penny Opera; Infernal Machine; Tiger at the Gates; Antigone; No Exit; Bald Soprano, undated (Box 6, U-matic 37-13.0072)
  - Sunrise Semester Tapes: Tom Bishop: The Three Penny Opera; The Infernal Machine; Tiger at the Gates; Antigone; No Exit; The Bald Soprano, undated (Box 6, U-matic 37-13.0073)
  - Tom Bishop: Journal de Voyages a New York, undated (Box 6, U-matic 37-13.0074)
- La Maison Française Sound Recordings, 1966-1999
  This series, dated 1966-1999, consists of audio recordings of lectures, readings, symposia, roundtable discussions, and gallery talks on contemporary perspectives of the French and Francophone language, literature, and civilization held at New York University's La Maison Française. These audio recordings document events featuring literary, artistic, and political figures, including Robert Badinter, Roland Barthes, and Nathalie Sarraute, in addition to other distinguished guests such as, Michel Butor, Hélène Cixous, Maryse Condé, and Amélie Nothomb.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Sarraute, Nathalie: "Forme et Contenu du Roman", March 29, 1966 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0090)
  - Butor, Michel, April 2, 1966 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0091)
  - Barthes, November 14, 1967 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0092, 37-13.0093)
  - Girard, René, February 20, 1968 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0094)
  - Todorov, Tzvetan, November 9, 1972 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0095)
  - Leenhardt, Jacques, January 8, 1980 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0096)
  - Stablein, Patricia, December 4, 1980 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0097)
  - Sarraute, Nathalie: "Enfance: L'usage de la parole", September 23, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0098)
  - Hocquard, Emmanuel, September 25, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0099)
  - Morin, Edgar, September 30, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0100)
  - Sarraute, Nathalie, October 2, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0101)
  - Kilborne, Benjamin, October 7, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0102)
  - Porter, Melinda, October 14, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0103)
  - Arrabel, Fernando, October 16, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0104)
  - Award Winning French Novelists: Besson, etc., October 21, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0105)
  - Award Winning French Novelists: Braudeau, Queffelec, October 23, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0106)
  - Léotard, October 29, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0107)
  - Leenhardt, Jacques, November 11, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0108)
  - Djebar, Assia, November 18, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0109)
  - Bonnefoy, Yves, November 20, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0110)
  - Butor, Michel, December 3, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0111)
  - Kis, Danilo, December 4, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0112)
  - Bellour, Raymond, December 9, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0113)
  - Bruckner, Pascal, December 11, 1986 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0114)
  - Deneys, Anne, January 13, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0115)
  - Schor, Naomi, February 10, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0116)
  - Myrent, Glenn, February 17, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0117)
  - Finas, Lucette, February 24, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0118)
  - Rosenblum, Robert, February 26, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0119)
  - Rybalka, Michel, March 3, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0120)
  - Lamont, Rosette, March 5, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0121)
  - Cohen-Solal, Annie, March 10, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0122)
  - Seguin, March 16, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0123)
  - Sicard, October 12, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0124)
  - Baumgartaer, Emmanuelle, October 15, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0125)
  - Papert, Emma, October 20, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0126)
  - Mitterand, Henri, November 5, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0127)
  - Rolland, November 10, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0128)
  - Bruckner, Pascal: "Malaise dans la Culture", November 12, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0129)
  - Echenoz, Jean, November 19, 1987 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0130)
  - Milly, Jean, January 12, 1988 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0131)
  - Avni, Ora, January 14, 1988 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0132)
  - Capretz, Pierre, March 3, 1988 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0133)
  - Coste, Didier, April 19, 1988 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0134)
  - Genette, Gérard, April 26, 1988 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0135)
  - Schmitt, Jean-Claude, May 3, 1988 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0136)
  - Scarpetta, Guy: "Enquête sur la création contemporaine", September 19, 1989 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0137)
  - Roger, Philippe: "Roland Barthes: dix ans après", September 25, 1989 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0138)
  - Lejeune, Philippe: "Enquête sur le journal personnel", September 26, 1989 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0139)
  - Bris, Gonzague: "Lafayette: La Stature de la Liberté", October 26, 1989 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0140)
  - Thomasset, Claude: "Sexualité et discours médical dans la France du Moyen Age", November 2, 1989 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0141)
  - Gaillard, Françoise: "Balzac: un sémiologue de la société", November 13, 1989 (Box 8, Audiocassette 37-13.0142)
  - Thomas, Chantal: "Sade, Casanova: Variation sur l'esprit de libertinage au 18éme siècle", November 16, 1989 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0143)
  - d'Aboville, Benoit: "Quelle Europe pour quels Européens? Le débat en France et en Europe sur l'avenir du continent", November 28, 1989 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0144)
  - Dallenbach, Lucien: "Primitisme dans le roman du vingtième siècle: une lecture de Claude Simon", December 7, 1989 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0145)
  - Lochard, Eric: "Informatique humanités, un mariage forcé? Rapports présents et à venir", December 11, 1989 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0146)
  - Marini, Marcelle: "Georges Perc: entre autobiographie et récit d'analyse", December 12, 1989 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0147)
  - Finas, Lucette: "Dénouer: Balzac et Flaubert", January 30, 1990 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0148)
  - Roubichou, Gérard: "Discours parodique et discours romanesque en relisant Queneau", February 8, 1990 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0149)
  - Nesci, Catherine: "Inter Mimologiques Nodier, dériseur sensé?", February 27, 1990 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0150)
  - Apostolides, Jean-Marie: "Mai 68 et la modernité", March 1, 1990 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0151)
  - Doubrovsky, Serge: "En dialogue avec Tom Bishop (Chair, Dept. of French, NYU: Le Livre brisé: un roman à deux)", April 3, 1990 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0152)
  - Green, André: "Des Mouches aux Mots: Sartre et la psychanalyse", April 12, 1990 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0153)
  - Genette, Gérard: "La définition du style", April 17, 1990 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0154)
  - Yampolsky, Mikhail: "Questions au cinéma soviétique contemporain", November 5, 1990 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0155)
  - Prendergast, Christopher: "Circulating in the (pre/post) Modern City: from Jules Laforgue to Michel de Certeau", November 19, 1990 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0156)
  - Bernstein, Richard: "France: Why Fragile, Why Glorious?", January 24, 1991 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0157)
  - Scharfman, Ronnie: "Rewriting the Césaires: Caribbean Discoure in Daniel Maximin's L'Isolé Soleil", January 31, 1991 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0158)
  - Mitterand, Henri: "Poétique de l'espace romaneque: La bête humaine d'Emile Zola", February 12, 1991 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0159)
  - Tannery, Claude: "Malraux, l'art, la mort et la vie", February 20, 1991 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0160)
  - Zink, Michel: "Autour des chansons du XVe siècle: le traditionnel et le populaire", March 5, 1991 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0161)
  - Gaillard, Françoise: "Barthes: une vie", March 7, 1991 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0162)
  - Laurent, Jacques: "Le roman?", March 19, 1991 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0163)
  - Fleutiaux, Pierrette: "Nous sommes éternels", September 29, 1992 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0164)
  - Weber, Eugen: "Was Renan wrong? Reflections on the Use of Obsolete Ideas", May 7, 1991 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0165)
  - Cixous, Hélène: "Quelle heure est-il? Discussion in French of theoretical problems", September 29, 1992 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0166)
  - Foucault Roundtable, February 9, 1993 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0167)
  - Brooks, Peter, February 25, 1993 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0168)
  - Fassin, Eric, April 14, 1994 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0169)
  - Bruckner, Pascal: "Yugoslavia: Europe Faces its Old Demons (Florence Gould Lecture)", September 15, 1994 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0170)
  - Chatelet, Noëlle: "Manger: un langage d'un corps (Florence Gould Lecture)", September 20, 1994 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0171)
  - Finas, Lucette: "Du goût à la lettre: Brillat-Savarin et Huysmans", September 22, 1994 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0172)
  - Cone, Michèle: "Max Jacob and his artistic circle (Galler Talk)", October 4, 1994 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0173)
  - Butor, Michel: "Après le roman (American Society of the French Legion of Honor Lecture)", October 6, 1994 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0174)
  - Vitz, Evelyn: "Reading, Telling, Playing, Singing! Medieval Romance in Performance (Co-sponsored with the Medieval and Renaissance Studies Program)", October 24, 1994 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0175)
  - Hersant, Yves: "Voyageurs des lumières: sur les routes d'Europe au dix-huitième siècle", November 8, 1994 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0176)
  - Milner, Max: "Les dispositifs voyeuristes dans le récit balzacien", November 29, 1994 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0177)
  - Condé, Maryse: "Lectures de textes et discussions en français", February 13, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0178)
  - Badinter, Robert: "Center for French Civilization and Culture", February 17, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0179)
  - Debray, Régis: "Pour une histoire du regard en Occident", February 21, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0180)
  - Finkielkraut, Alain: "Le Destin de la culture", February 28, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0181)
  - Gaillard, Françoise: "Proust et le temps perdu", March 2, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0182)
  - Poiret-Delpech, Bertrand: "Culture et barbarie (Florence Gould Lecture)", March 7, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0183)